<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ASRG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ASRG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/asrg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Declaration of Solidarity with Palestine ✊</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/palestine-2024-03-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/posts/palestine-2024-03-13/</guid>
      <description>Figure: Data published by the UN shows locations of damaged and destroyed schools in Gaza Strip. Schools documented to have received internally displaced people (IDPs) are marked by larger icons (red and yellow). Schools that received IDPs and were also damaged are marked red. The map only shows schools that have been damaged. (Forensic Architecture, 2024) | Image Source: https://forensic-architecture.org/investigation/humanitarian-violence-in-gaza Solidarity with Palestine # The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) has been and continues to be in solidarity with the people of Palestine.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/about/</guid>
      <description>The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) is an ongoing, conspiratorial, aesthetico-political, practice-led research framework focused on the intersection of digital culture and information technology. # It explores the diversity of practices and the role of artistic activism in exposing, critiquing, disrupting and countering the encroachments of algorithmic systems of power, control and exploitation, with the objective of strengthening, promoting and protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms by offering interdisciplinary pathways to empower the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Officers Faces (POF)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/police_officers-faces-pof/</guid>
      <description>Police Officers Faces (POF) A large-scale face recognition dataset containing of approximately 90,000 headshot photos of thousands of police officers. This dataset is intended as a tool to empower community members engaged in copwatch and other counter-surveillance practices. Posted: Jun 17, 2024. Modified: Jun 28, 2024 One hundred sample images from the “POF” face recognition dataset. Faces have been redacted to protect privacy. One hundred sample images from the “POF” face recognition dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intertwined Feedback Loops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/intertwined-feedback-loops/</guid>
      <description>Intertwined Feedback Loops A series of intertwined feedback loops that unfold from several interrelated briefs for intellectual and practical exploration. Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Jun 15, 2024 Context # The Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG) has drawn a series of intertwined feedback loops that unfold from several interrelated briefs for intellectual and practical exploration. These critically subversive flowcharts have been informed by research on digital labour exploitation, invisible infrastructures, techno-colonialism, automatised technologies of tracking, monitoring and surveillance and many other contemporary phenomena at the intersection between technology and society.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/manifesto-on-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>Manifesto on “Algorithmic Sabotage” A preliminary version of 10 statements, numbered 0 to 9, on the principles, strategies and aesthetics of “algorithmic sabotage”. Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Jun 16, 2024 Download the English language version of the Manifesto as a printable PDF | Graphic: © Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group | The typeface used in the document is Avara from Velvetyne Foundry: https://velvetyne.fr/fonts/avara/ Context # A preliminary version of ten statements, numbered 0 to 9, on the principles, strategies and aesthetics of “algorithmic sabotage”.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage”</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/asrg/theorizing-algorithmic_sabotage/</guid>
      <description>Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage” An urgent intervention rooted in the militant liberation struggles of the most oppressed within the arena of global computational racial capitalism. Posted: Jun 13, 2024. Modified: Jun 15, 2024 A crowd in San Francisco’s Chinatown surrounded a Waymo robotaxi on Saturday, breaking windows and throwing fireworks inside, setting the vehicle ablaze | Image Source: https://sfstandard.com/2024/02/12/waymo-san-francisco-burned-arrests/ Context # Based on the work of the Algorithmic Sabotage Research Group (ASRG), Theorizing “Algorithmic Sabotage” is an urgent intervention rooted in the militant liberation struggles of the most oppressed within the arena of global computational racial capitalism, with the aim of creating and defending spaces of autonomy for the development and dissemination of radical and counter-hegemonic social imaginaries through the universal prefigurative techno-politicisation of the class base, for the manifestation of direct, vigorous struggles of combative algorithmic agency and resistance against the hyper-abstracted optimisations and capitalisation of life without limits by the techno-elite regimes, the mathematised processes of alienation and the turn towards to algorithmic fascism.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>